我是奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years in hell,
我回来只有一个目标
I have returned home with only one goal--
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但我之前的方法还不够
But my old approach wasn't enough.
翻译   冰蓝  SophiaSaaaga  西西  小暴徒
我得成为另一个人
I had to become someone else.
我得成为另一个存在
I had to become something else.
翻译  Reginamoon  Michale 天青月白  Silence
我得成为绿箭侠
I had to become the Green Arrow.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously, on "Arrow"...
校对  西西  Michale  苹果果    精校  陈小圈
我要知道我来这干什么  沃勒在哪
I want to know what I'm doing here. Where's Waller?
你的工作就是要潜入该区域  然后上报
Your job is to infiltrate the area, and report back.
时间轴风吹来的那片云
媒体把他们称为"幽灵"
The media has been calling them a Ghost.
特效&后期   咖啡Lee   初校/总监   苹果果
这些人是前所未见的
They're like nothing we'd ever seen before.
我们需要绿箭
We need the Arrow.
我掌管那些...
I'm the one who controls--
你们叫他们什么
now what do you people call them?
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
幽灵
The Ghosts?
我是达米恩·达克
I'm Damian Darhk.
大屠杀
Mass murder?
杀戮无辜者  我当初没答应做这些
Killing innocents? I didn't sign up for this.
你答应听从我的指令
You signed up to follow my instructions.
如果我不帮你呢
And if I don't help you?
你别无选择
You don't have a choice.
六个月前  绿箭死了
Six months ago, the Arrow died,
但他的理念没有消逝
but what he stood for didn't.
我宣布
I am declaring my intention
为这座城市而战
to fight for this city.
我想要一个代号
I want a code name.
什么
What?!
大家都有新代号  就连你也有新的代号
Everyone's got a code name; You even got a new one.
我想要一个代号
I want a code name.
找到炸弹  然后我们再谈这事
Find the bomb, and then we'll talk.
我在扫描他们常用的频率
I'm scanning frequency signatures.
我知道你不会跟我谈这事
I just know we're not going to talk about it.
约翰  有人跑了
John, you've got a runner.
我这就去
I'm on it.
找到了  幽灵常用的频率在一楼
Got it. The Ghost frequency of choice is on the ground level.
我敢肯定那就是炸弹
Ten'll get you twenty it's the bomb.
我不是说  我很兴奋
I don't mean that it's the bomb,
像是好事  有炸弹哦
like it's good, like it's the bomb!
我是说那是炸药
I mean like it's the explosives.
知道了  一楼
Got it. Ground floor.
你最好快点  根据我读到的信号强度
You better move it. The signal strength I'm reading,
他们都能炸掉中城的污水厂了
they can blow the treatment plant from Central City.
搞定了  让狄格尔下来拆除
It's done. Get Diggle down here to handle the dismantling.
他好像也需要一个代号
You know, it seems like he could use a code name, too.
让他下来吧
Just get him down here.
绿 箭
第四季  第二集
拯救城市的供水
Well, saving the city's water supply,
真是忙了一晚上  一早上啊
that's an honest night's--morning's work.
但不管我们做什么  这些幽灵还是源源不断
Yeah, but no matter what we do to these Ghosts, they keep coming.
我们今晚还是做得很棒
We still did a good job tonight.
还不够好
Yeah, not good enough.
我能和你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
感觉你今晚就是想见血
Kind of felt like you were out there for blood tonight.
你跟这些幽灵
Look, you haven't been
打交道的时间不如我们长
dealing with these ghosts as long as we have.
如果我手下留情  情况会变得更糟糕
If I go easy on them, things are going to end bad really fast.
我担心  如果你继续这样
I'm worried that if you keep going the way that you're going,
迟早有人会死在你手上
you're going to put one of them down permanently.
我知道底线在哪  好吗
I know where the line is, ok?
已经九点了  丹福斯太太和麦迪逊
And look, it's almost 9:00. Mrs. Danforth and Madison
一小时后就会来我们家
are going to be at our house in like an hour,
我要么继续听你说教  要么去洗澡
so I have time for one of your lectures or a shower.
我选择洗澡
I pick shower.
没事吧
Is everything ok?
你看起来真美
You look nice.
今天是我回帕尔默科技的第一天
It's my first day back at Palmer Tech.
我今天得专横点
I get to be bossy today,
因为我就是数十亿美元的公司的老板
because I am the boss of a multi-billion dollar corporation.
我知道我该紧张  但我不紧张
I know I should be nervous, I know, but I'm not.
我其实很激动
I'm actually really excited.
你该激动
You should be excited.
所以我给你准备了
That's why I got you the...
第一天当上老板的蕨类植物
first day as a boss fern.
还有
And...
打包了你的午餐
packed your lunch.
你是谁啊
Who are you?
回答我
Answer me!
好吧
All right.
已落地
<准备潜入
什么
What?!
>潜入什么
<自己看着办.让他们信任你
有没搞错
Come on.
麦迪逊  学校怎么样
Madison, how's school?
挺好的  我五月毕业
It's good. I graduate in May
会拿到古代哲学的学位
with a degree in ancient philosophy.
古代哲学
Ancient philosophy?
你不是想做贾老板的备用舞者吗
Um, what happened to your dream of being J.T.'s back-up dancer?
显然那还是后备计划
Oh, that's still plan B, obviously.
见到你俩真好
It is so lovely to see you two.
真的  我们很久没见了
Really, it's been far too long.
西娅和我很高兴你联系我们
Well, Thea and I were glad you got in touch.
但我们有点惊讶
Yeah, we were, um, a little surprised, though.
我承认  跟我最好朋友的
Well, I admit that reconnecting with the son and daughter
儿女再度相见
of one of my dearest friends
并不是我想见你们的唯一原因
is not...the only reason that I wanted to see you.
准备听点疯狂的吧
And here comes the crazy.
上周  跟城里其他人一样
Last week, like the rest of the city,
我看到绿箭侠在电视上的声明
I saw the Green Arrow's broadcast.
就像醍醐灌顶...
And it hit me--
如果那个人可以接替绿箭侠
if that man could take up the Arrow's mantle,
我也可以接替你们的母亲
I could take up your mother's.
怎么说
Um, how?
去竞选市长
By running for mayor.
我就说吧  疯狂至极
See, I told you--crazy.
显然没人跟我竞争
No one's opposing me, obviously,
但选举过程还是要有的
but there will still need to be an election.
没有人去竞选是有原因的
There's a very good reason that no one else is running.
近三任市长都被杀了
The last three mayors have been killed.
还不算上周被杀的市领导
To say nothing of the city's leadership last week.
所以我们此时更需要有位市长啊
Which is exactly why we need a mayor more than ever.
我想站出来
I want to step forward.
请你们支持我
And I'm asking for your support.
你们本人
You guys look bigger than you did
比从我的电脑屏幕上看要大多了
when you were on my computer screen.
就从本季度的财政状况开始吧
Perhaps we should begin with this quarter's financials.
谢谢
Thank you. Uh...
我知道我不是商科毕业
I know I don't have a business degree,
也不是学会计或者工商管理
or an accounting degree or an MBA,
但是这看起来非常非常糟糕
but this looks very, very bad.
这段时间对星城所有人都很艰难
These are hard times for everyone in Star City.
我们公司也没能幸免
This company's not immune.
幸运的是  霍特先生给我们指了一条明路
Fortunately, Mr. Holt had devised us a way out.
很好
Oh, goody.
大家好
Um, hello.
我并不是董事会成员
I'm actually not a member of the board.
我在设计研发部门
I work in the design innovations department.
跟斯莫克小姐说说你的算法
Tell Miss Smoak about your algorithm.
其实很简单
It's, uh, pretty simple, actually.
我用专业化的人工智能算了一下最大利润
I use specialized A.I. to determine maximum profits,
是按最少的劳动力
which can be derived
推导出来的
with a minimum amount of workforce deduction.
抱歉  我或许能解释地再清楚点
Sorry. I probably could have explained that better.
不用  我懂了
No, I got the jist.
你得出了一份裁员名单
You came up with a list of people that you'd like me to fire.
说人员精减会好听点
Workforce reduction has a nicer sound to it.
读起来很顺的
It just kind of rolls off the tongue.
我们目前唯一要减少的
Well, the only thing we'll be reducing
就是各位的分红
is all of your bonuses to start.
我们已经减薪了
We've already been down that road
其他的办法也都试过但无果  斯莫克小姐
and exhausted all other avenues, Miss Smoak.
我回到这间公司
I didn't come back to this company
不是为了让这里的员工失业
to put the people who work here out of work.
我来是为了保护雷·帕尔默的遗产
I came here to protect Ray Palmer's legacy.
如果我们不能大幅减少开支
And if we do not dramatically reduce our costs
或提高利润  就没有遗产可保护了
or increase our profits, there won't be a legacy to protect.
只有我有不祥的预感吗
Am I the only one that has a bad feeling about this?
自告奋勇做市长
I mean, signing up to be mayor of this town
就像报名上泰坦尼克号一样
is like asking to be part of "The Titanic."
你也听到我试图阻止她了
Well, you heard me try to talk her out of running.
可我们同意出席她的竞选发布会
I'm pretty sure that got covered up
明摆着就是支持了
by telling her we'd be at her big announcement.
谢谢
Thank you.
丹福斯
非常感谢各位
Thank you all so much.
在过去的六个月里
For the past six months,
市政厅市长的位置一直空着
the Mayor's office at city hall has stood vacant,
等待有人代表星城站出来
waiting for someone to step forward on behalf of Star City.
今天  我与各位一同在这里
And today, I am here with all of you
就是想说  我站出来了
to tell you that I am stepping forward.
两年前
Two years ago,
我痛失挚友莫伊拉·奎恩
I lost my good friend Moira Queen,
她也曾是市长候选人
who was also a candidate for mayor.
我至今仍被她的善良打动
And I remain inspired by her kind heart,
她为这座城市无私奉献
and her selfless devotion to this city.
子弹是从那里射来的
Shots came from up there.
不  不  你去保护杰西卡  我来对付他们
No, no, you protect Jessica, I've got this.
枪击只是声东击西
The shots are just a distraction!
那里没有幽灵
There's no ghosts up here!
等等  你不是她的安保人员
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait-- you're not in her detail.
-到中庭去  -奥利弗  你怎么...
- Get back to the atrium! - Oliver, how...
自卫课上学的
Um, self-defense classes.
她刚宣布竞选
She announces her candidacy,
两秒钟后  就有人要杀她
and two seconds later, someone's trying to kill her?
即使对于星城而言也算是记录了
That must be a record, even for our city.
她不打算放弃竞选  所以这事还没完
She's not dropping out of the race, so this isn't over.
我父亲派了人保护她
My father has a protective detail on her.
但发布会上也有人保护
Yeah, but even with protection at the announcement,
她并不安全
she didn't seem to be too safe.
只有我一个人觉得  对市政领导候选人的枪击
Is it just me, or is the shooting of a potential city leader
感觉很像幽灵所为吗
feeling a little ghosty?
那个人没戴面具  所以...
This guy wasn't wearing a mask, so...
还有另一个不同点
There was something else different about him.
他留下了罪证
He left behind evidence.
他的指纹
Fingerprints.
你怎么让车主把挡风玻璃给你的
How'd you get the owner to part with his windshield?
我买下了他的车
I bought his truck.
此乃女友是坐拥亿万资产的老板的
It's one of the benefits of your girlfriend inheriting
众多好处之一
a multi-billion dollar conglomerate.
我们现在有钱了
We have money now.
我不觉得这钱花得值
I don't exactly think that was money well spent.
这些指纹对我们没什么帮助
I don't think these prints are going to do us any good.
什么鬼
What the hell?
我不是指纹鉴别专家
I am not an expert,
但这位朋友可能切掉了自己的指尖
but I think our new friend may have cut off his fingertips
搞了一点混搭
and played a little bit of mix and match.
我会继续追查
I'll keep digging;
也许这就是他的作案手法  可能是个线索
maybe this is an M.O., that'll tell us something.
同时我们还要增援星城警局
In the meantime, we backstop the SCPD.
西娅是对的
Thea was right--
杰西卡需要警力以外的保护
Jessica needs more than the police can offer.
她现在正受到保护性监禁  而且我很确定我父亲
She's in protective custody, and I'm pretty sure my father
不会乐意我们在他的分局外监视的
wouldn't be in favor of us staking out his precinct.
我会跟他谈的
I'll talk to him.
好吧
Oh, yeah.
我相信你们一定会谈得很愉快
That'll definitely go over well.
在我们抓到犯人之前
Mrs. Danforth is under our protection 24/7
丹福斯夫人将受到我们全天候的保护
until this nut bar is in cuffs.
你有空吗
Do you have a minute?
我看到你的电视首秀了
Caught your TV debut.
看来你决定留下来了
Guess you decided to stick around.
这次会和以前不一样
It's going to be different this time.
是啊  因为你有了个新名字
Yeah, yeah, sure, well, 'cause you got a new name now,
还带个颜色
right, with a color.
绿箭侠
Green Arrow.
名字挺顺口的
It's catchy.
杰西卡·丹福斯是我的朋友
Jessica Danforth is a friend.
我们想帮忙保护她
We would like to help keep her safe.
考虑到星城面临的危机
With everything the city's facing,
我觉得你应该用上一切可能的力量
I thought you could use all the help you could get.
你离开了那么久
You've been gone.
根本不知道我们面临的是什么
You don't know what this city's facing.
我不是说星城不需要拯救
And I'm not saying it doesn't need saving,
可是躲在面具后的人是无法拯救城市的
but a guy hiding behind a mask isn't going to get it done.
这座城市需要的是
What this city needs is someone willing
一个愿意站在明处
to stand up in the light of day,
而不是潜伏在暗处的人
not a guy lurking around in the shadows.
你说这回你会变得不一样吗
You say you're going to be different this time, huh?
怎么不一样
How?
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你来晚了
You're late.
抱歉  我只是在重新看之前的数字...
I know. Sorry, I was looking at the numbers again, and--
你是说你那个神奇的裁减算法
Oh, you mean the numbers of people
计算出的待解雇人数吗
that your magic downsizing algorithm is making us fire today.
裁减  你以为我  你以为...
Downsizing? You think I-- you think I--
让我跟你说清楚
Let's get one thing straight.
在这里只有我可以
The only person who is allowed to talk
结结巴巴说不上话
in sentence fragments around here is me.
我弄出这个算法是为了建立一个产业值矩阵
I developed my algorithm to create a value matrix.
是为了讨论如何涨薪
To argue for company-wide pay increases, raises.
丹尼斯先生把我的算法倒了过来
Mr. Dennis turned it around
让我用它来决定裁掉哪些人
and had me use it to figure out who to fire.
所以这不是你的主意
So this wasn't your idea?
我是想让员工们拿到更多的钱
I was trying to get people to get paid more,
而不是没有工资
not paid nothing.
我是卡拉·格罗文斯
Hi, I'm Carla Groves.
我的主管让我来见你
My supervisor asked me to come see you.
是的  没错
Hi. Yes. Um...
我不知道要怎么开口...
I don't know quite how to say this--
我被炒了
I'm fired.
你说话真直
But clearly you do.
他们说公司只会裁掉更多的人
As rumors go, downsizing ones tend to go viral.
很抱歉
I am very sorry.
我回来不是为了让员工失业
I didn't come back here to put people out of work.
但我希望  裁掉一些人
But I am hoping that by losing a few jobs,
能从长远上保住更多人的工作
I can save many, many more.
你裁掉的不只是一些人吧
That looks like a little more than a few.
没错
Yes.
现在公司情况很困难
The company is going through a difficult time.
我知道  当我们听说你要回来的时候
I know. And when we heard you were coming back,
我们都以为会有起色
we thought things were going to get a lot better.
看来我们想错了
Guess we were wrong.
我还是很饿
I'm still hungry.
我是不是不应该觉得饿
Is it wrong that I'm still hungry?
约翰
John?
十分钟内他们就要换岗了
Shift changes in 10 minutes.
这一整周你好像都一直绷着
You know, for the past week, you've been pretty intense.
你打算告诉我  发生了什么吗
Are you going to tell me what's going on?
别说是因为奥利弗回来了
And don't tell me it's because Oliver's back.
他回来我的确不开心
Well, I'm not happy Oliver's back.
这点大家都看得很清楚
Yeah, you weren't exactly subtle about that.
别管了  劳蕾尔
Just let it go, Laurel.
不能不管  因为我们不能有所隐瞒
No. Because we don't keep secrets, remember?
约翰
John.
到底怎么了
What's going on?
还记得上周奥利弗说起那个达克吗
Remember last week, when Oliver was telling us about Darhk?
他说他的追随者就像蜂群一样
He said he had a hive of followers.
一个名叫蜂巢的组织派人杀死了我哥哥
An organization called H.I.V.E. killed my brother.
我刚知道这事
I didn't know.
你觉得这是巧合吗
Do you think it's some kind of coincidence?
不  我已经查了他们两年了
No. I've been looking into this organization for two years now.
什么都没查到  不过我还是设法
All dead ends. But what I did manage
查到了达克那些幽灵跟这组织的关系
to dig up tracks with what we know about Darhk's ghosts.
他们是蜂巢的人
They're H.I.V.E.
奥利弗和费莉西蒂知道吗
Do Oliver and Felicity know?
不知道
No.
你已经调查了这事两年
You've been investigating this
却从没告诉过他们
for two years and you haven't told them?
这是我自己的家事  劳蕾尔
It's a family thing, Laurel.
我觉得在所有人之中  你最能理解
I would think you, of all people, would understand
当手足死去  要隐瞒秘密是何种滋味
keeping secrets when it comes to the death of a sibling.
我理解
I do.
正因为我理解  我才要告诉你
And because I do, I can tell you,
肩负着那样的重担
carrying a burden like that,
不可能会有好结局
it never ends in any way but bad.
那真是一场好戏
That was quite the show.
调虎离山的机枪  伪装成保镖
False machine gun, impersonating a bodyguard;
你很有戏剧天赋啊  马尚先生
you have the flair for the dramatic, Mr. Machin.
我得承认那一点
I will give you that.
非常遗憾最后一切未果
Too bad it was all for nothing.
一半的酬劳已经转入你的账户了
Half of your fee has been wired into your account.
这事和钱无关
This isn't about money for me.
我明白
Oh, I know.
你带着承诺来找我
You came to me with promises.
你希望向我的组织展示你的能耐
You wanted to impress yourself to my organization,
但你失败了
and you failed.
我还没做完呢
I'm not done yet!
你就...
Just...
再给我点时间
give me more time.
我会确保杰西卡·丹福斯退出竞选的
I will make sure that Jessica Danforth does not run for mayor.
很好
Very well.
但是  给你个忠告
However, a word of caution.
我不确定瑞克·皮恩佐洛是怎么管理他的组织的
I'm not sure how Rick Pinzolo runs his operation,
但是蜂巢从不给人第三次机会
but H.I.V.E. does not believe in third chances.
晚安
Good night.
我和狄格尔通过话了
I spoke to Diggle.
警局那边没什么进展
No movement at the precinct.
没关系
That's all right.
我也许有了点进展
I may have some movement here.
我注意到有些黏黏的东西
I noticed something tacky
在那个人留在挡风玻璃上的手掌印里
on the palm print our guy left on the windshield.
黏黏的
Tacky?
像是某种残留物
Like a residue.
哪一种
What kind?
纤维素
Cellulose.
不过这玩意的成分很特别
Ohh, except this formulation is special.
它的分子结构获得过专利
The molecular structure's been patented.
谁获得的
By who?
帕尔默科技
Palmer Technologies.
实际上是它的一个子公司  帕尔默纸业
A subsidiary, actually. Palmer Paper.
几个月前我不得不关掉造纸厂以消减成本
I had to shut down the mill a couple months ago as a cost cutting measure.
那间造纸厂在哪里
Where's the paper mill?
提高警惕  他有某种电击武器
Stay sharp. He has some sort of electricity weapon.
照片中的人  你见过吗
The man in the photo, you seen 'em?
我很少看见什么  我喜欢睡觉
I don't see much-- I like my sleep.
但那个人  他看见的东西多
But that guy, he sees a lot.
他在这交易  做了很多生意
He deals out of here, does a lot of business.
我们得问你几个问题
We need to ask you a few questions.
滚开  怪胎
Step off, freak.
你在这里见过这个人吗  我要他的名字
Have you seen this guy here? I want a name.
你们这些戴面具的  觉得自己是管事儿的
You masks, you think you're in charge.
没错  也许之前是的  但以后不是了
Yeah, well, maybe you were, but not anymore.
现在有新的戴面具的管事了
There are new masks in charge--
快手
Speedy!
你在这里见过这个人吗
Have you seen this guy here?
你还想要你的手臂吗
Do you still want to use your arm?!
让他走
Let him go.
还觉得自己是管事儿的吗
Still think you're in charge?
你给我出去
Hey! Get out of here!
我找到我们那位古怪先生的身份了
I got an ID on our Mr. Creepy.
我还以为他的指纹都被破坏了呢
I thought his fingerprints were all screwed up.
是被混合了  但我超爱玩拼图
Mixed up, but I have an obsession with Jigsaw puzzles.
朗尼·马尚  兼职的黑帮杀手
Lonnie Machin. Part time mob enforcer,
全职的疯子
full time crazy pants.
为波提纳尔家族  三合会
Done jobs for the Bertinellis, the Triad,
以及瑞克·皮恩佐洛干事
and Rick Pinzolo.
我们得谈谈这事
We're going to talk about this.
我们得好好谈一谈刚刚发生的事
We're going to have the conversation about what just happened.
刚刚发生的事就是那家伙有信息
What just happened was that guy had information
而我试图撬开他的嘴
and I was trying to get it out of him.
你弄断了他的胳膊
You broke his arm.
他是在拖时间
He was stalling!
他是被吓到了  过来
He was scared. Come here.
你干什么
What are you doing?!
我得给你看些东西
I need to show you something.
在水厂那里  你干掉了一个幽灵
At the water plant, you took down a ghost.
你本可靠一个简单的解除武装技巧解决的
You could have done it with a very simple disarmament technique,
像这样
like this--
但是西娅  你不是这样做的
But Thea, that's not what you did.
你走了极端
You went overboard
用了一系列技巧  目的只有一个...
with a series of techniques designed to do one thing
致残
cripple!
奥利弗...
Oliver...
-够了  -过来
- That's enough! - Come on!
演示结束了
Demonstration's over.
好吧  对不起  抱歉  抱歉
Fine, sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
在拉斯伤害了你之后
After Ra's hurt you--
马尔科姆警告我不要把你带到南达尔巴特
Malcolm warned me not to take you to Nanda Parbat.
他说人们一旦进入了那个泉水
He said that when people go in the pit,
出来后他们就不是同一个人了
they don't come out the same.
而我之所以没告诉你
And I didn't tell you,
是因为我不想让你担忧
because I didn't want to worry about you.
你当时看起来很正常  西娅
You seemed normal, Thea,
我对天发誓  我以为一切都会好起来的
and I swear to God, i thought everything was going to be fine.
然后你就离开了
And then you left.
所以你知道吗
So you know what?
实际上你没资格对我评头论足
It doesn't really qualify you to judge me,
对其他人也没有
or anyone else!
发生什么事了
What's going on?
在南达尔巴特时西娅身上发生了什么
What happened to Thea in Nanda Parbat?
我做了该做的事
I did what I had to do--
来救我妹妹
save my sister.
奥利弗  那已经是半年前了
Oliver, that was six months ago.
为什么现在才对她有影响
Why is the pit only affecting her now?
可能是一点一点显现出来的
It's probably been showing up over time, subtly.
你想要怎么做
What do you want to do about it?
你  站起来
You! Hey! Stand down.
我想你已经知道肯尼怎么了
I guess you know what happened to Kenny.
别动  别动
Don't move, don't move!
闭嘴
Just shut up.
这是雷区  懂吗
It's a mine field, all right?
是地雷炸死了你们的朋友
That's what killed your friend.
那你是谁
And who the hell are you?
我的名字叫奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
三年前  我乘坐的游艇在暴风雨中沉没了
Three years ago, the yacht that I was on went down in a storm
我被冲到了这里  活了下来
and I washed up here. I survived.
带他去见瑞特  他会知道该怎么处理他的
Let's take him to Reiter. He'll know what to do with him.
你今天看起来真像是一个
Wow, you look like someone
要大刀阔斧裁员的人
who has to fire a whole mess of people today.
什么  不是的
What? Oh, no.
是要裁员  不过不是因为这事不爽
I mean, yes, but this isn't about this.
但我并不是说解雇十几个人
Not that firing a dozen people
会让我心情好转
is going to do much for my mood.
-其实  是二十多个  -什么
- Actually, it's two dozen. - What?!
那些纸正反面都有
The pages are double-sided.
肯定还有别的办法
There has to be another way.
公司里有那么多聪明的人
This many intelligent people in the company,
肯定有人能想出...
there has to be someone who...
斯莫克小姐  你还好吗
Miss Smoak, are you all right?
当然
Absolutely.
没事的
It's OK.
怎么了
What is?
我也在名单上  对吧
I'm on the list, aren't I?
是的  我很抱歉
Yeah. I'm so sorry.
没关系的
It's OK.
这样今天你就能少解雇一个人了  对吧
I mean, it's one less person that you have to fire today, right?
其实  在某种程度上来说  这也是好事
You know, actually, this is good news, in a way.
我丈夫会很高兴的
My husband will be thrilled.
这样我们就可以去期待已久的旅行了
This way we can take that trip that he's been wanting to go on.
当然了  得我来开车
Of course, I'll have to drive.
你不用想办法宽慰我了
You don't have to try and make me feel better about this.
宽慰你什么
About what?
我也算是炒了自己鱿鱼
I sort of fired myself.
星城警局
你是来探监的吗
Come to visit me in my confinement?
我觉得你会想有人陪着你
I thought you could use some company.
然后说一句"我早就告诉过你"吗
And a little "I told you so?"
这个  我可没说
Oh, I, yeah, I didn't bring it.
既然提起来了  其实你现在退出也不晚
With that being said, it's not too late for you to drop out.
那会给大家什么印象
And send what message?
除了星城的诸多问题
That on top of the city's other problems,
我们还向恐怖分子屈服吗
we give into terrorism?
这里的市民不应受到这样的待遇
The people here deserve better.
他们需要勇敢的人站出来
They deserve someone to be brave for them.
这是绿箭侠的责任
That's what the Green Arrow's for.
这还不够
Oh, it's not enough.
是的  绿箭侠冒着生命危险
Yes, the Green Arrow risked his life
来保护城市里的人
to keep the people of the city safe,
可是  谁能激励他们呢
but... who inspires them?
谁来保证
You know, who works to
这座城市还值得被拯救呢
make sure that there's a city worth saving?
谁能让星城成为一个
Who's there to make Star City a place
我女儿愿意称之为家的地方呢
that my daughter wants to call home?
麦迪逊呢
Where is Madison?
在图书馆  可怜的孩子还有期末考试
Oh, library. The poor kid had finals,
所以我之前送她回学校了
so I sent her back to school.
别担心
Don't worry--
兰斯队长派了足够的警察保护她
Captain Lance sent her with more than enough cops to keep her safe.
或许你应该给她打个电话
Maybe you should call her.
妈妈 来电
绑架了我女儿的人
To the man who took my daughter,
拜托了  我求求你
please, I am begging you,
求你放了我的宝贝
please, let my baby go.
她是我的全部
She's all I have.
她是我的整个世界
She's my whole world.
他用某种武器杀死了护送她的警察
He killed the officer escorting her with some kind of weapon.
先用5000伏电击枪
Shot them up with 5,000 volts,
然后又割喉
slit their throats for good measure.
他的名字叫朗尼·马尚
His name is Lonnie Machin.
我需要知道你是怎么得到这情报的吗
Do I even want to know where you got that Intel?
靠你自己处理不了这事  你清楚的
You can't do this alone. You know that.
现在  已经有两个人倒下了
Now, two of your guys are down.
让我们帮忙吧
Now let us help.
这是什么地方
Where's this place?
去那边
Over there.
巴伦  这家伙说他是
Baron, this guy says he's--
奥利弗·奎恩
Oliver Queen.
你们没认出他吗
You don't recognize him?
这人在外面的世界里
This man's a minor celebrity
可是小有名气的
on the other side of the world.
你不是应该死了吗
You're supposed to be dead.
差一点
Nearly was.
谢谢你救了我
Thank you for rescuing me.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
我们不是要救你
but we're not rescuing you.
你回家后做的第一件事就是
First thing you do once you get home
告诉别人我们在这里干什么
is tell people what it is we're doing here.
我不知道你们在这里做什么
I don't know what you're doing here.
即使是这样  我也不能放你回去
Be that as it may, I can't send you home.
至少现在不行
Not right now.
然而好消息是
Good news, though,
我并没有理由杀了你
I have no reason to kill you.
那你们要对我做什么
So what are you going to do to me?
问得好
Good question.
你在这里生存了三年
You've survived 3 years here,
独自一人
all alone.
这需要勇气和才智
That requires fortitude, intelligence--
这些品质对我来说很有用
qualities that are of use to me.
正好  我手下的一个人踩到地雷牺牲了
As it happens, one of my men stepped on a landmine.
你觉得接手这份工作怎么样
How would you like his job?
感谢你这么快就赶了过来
Thanks for coming on such short notice.
你干了什么
What did you do?
杰西卡·丹福斯的女儿在哪
Where is Jessica Danforth's daughter?
看到早些时候的新闻了吗
Did you catch the news earlier?
丹福斯女士乞求放他女儿条生路
Ms. Danforth begging for her daughter's life.
为了能救出女儿她可以做任何事
She'll do anything to get her back,
也可以不做一些事
or not do anything.
比如参加市长竞选
Like run for mayor.
我要做的只是打个电话
All I have to do is make a phone call.
现在我明白为何瑞克·皮恩佐洛驱逐了你
Now I see why Rick Pinzolo banished you.
你不懂得有些底线不能触碰
You're unaware that there are lines one does not cross.
我遇到了你的一个幽灵成员
I met one of your Ghosts.
拔掉他一颗牙后
After I took his tooth,
我们就蜂巢进行了一场有趣的交谈
we had an interesting conversation about H.I.V.E.
对话内容让我不相信你会尊重底线
I wasn't led to believe you respected lines.
我尊崇秩序  马尚先生
I respect order, Mr. Machin.
纪律和精度
Discipline, precision.
你很草率
You are sloppy.
你代表的只有混乱
All you represent is anarchy.
你惹了烂摊子  我劝你自己收拾干净
You made a mess. I suggest you clean it up.
不管怎样  我们的合作终止了
Either way, our relationship has concluded.
等等  你不能这样
Wait! You can't.
你的手放在我肩上了
You know your hand is on me.
收拾干净
Clean it up.
绑架了我女儿的人
To the man who took my daughter,
女儿遭遇绑架
拜托了  我求求你
please, I am begging you--
真让人伤心
That's heartbreaking.
求你放了我的宝贝
Please let my baby go.
还好吧
Are you ok?
我无法眼睁睁看着杰西卡经历这一切
Just can't stand watching Jessica go through that.
我想我被斯莱德·威尔逊绑架时
I feel like that's what my mom
我妈妈也是这种感受
felt like when Slade Wilson abducted me.
虽然这不是你问题的答案
That's not what you asked, though.
我没事
I'm fine.
你差点就骗过我了
Well, you could have fooled me.
西娅
Thea...
你在南达尔巴特发生了什么
what happened to you on Nanda Parbat?
奥利没告诉过你吗
Ollie didn't tell you?
你觉得他会吗
It's Ollie.
看来我还真是他妹妹
Well, I guess I really am his sister,
因为我也没跟你说
since I didn't tell you, either.
我只是
I just...
不愿再想起它
didn't want to re-live it.
想起什么
Re-live what?
拉斯  他
Ra's, he...
他杀了我
he killed me,
差点就得手了
or-- or almost did.
奥利说当时情况很糟糕
Ollie said that it was pretty bad.
然后拉斯说
And then Ra's
要用一种我不知道的东西
offered to use something-- I don't know,
让我起死回生
to bring me back.
他管这东西叫复活泉水
Something he calls the Lazarus Pit.
等等  也就是说如今你身上发生的
Wait, so what's happening to you now is--
是这个泉水的
is a side effect
副作用
from-- from this pit?
我想马尔科姆当时试图警告奥利  可他
Malcolm tried to warn Ollie, I guess, but he...
没听
didn't listen.
是啊  他当然不会听
No, of course he didn't.
他会想尽办法救活自己的妹妹
He would do anything to save his sister.
我发誓  哪怕那女孩身上有一道划痕
I swear, if there is even a scratch on that girl,
我敢断言...
so help me--
恐怕这件事不在我的掌控之内
I'm afraid that is out of my control.
是吗  那我也不受你控制了  我退出
Yeah? Well, so am I. I am out, I am all the way out!
我想我该提醒你麦迪逊·丹福斯
Well, I suppose you need a reminder that Madison Danforth
不是这座城市中唯一一个容易被伤害的女孩
is not the only vulnerable daughter in this city.
别碰我女儿
You stay the hell away from my daughter,
你个狗娘养的
you son of a bitch!
请注意措辞
Language.
这是什么
What is this?
丹福斯家女儿的所在位置
The location of the Danforth girl.
尽管我对你女儿发出诚挚的威胁
My sincere threat against your daughter not withstanding,
但是这种绑架毫无品位可言
this abduction lacks taste.
下次你我相遇
And the next time we meet,
相信我  会有下一次的
and make no mistake, there will be a next time,
记得要注意你的语气
remember to mind your tone.
有什么消息吗
Any news?
只有坏消息
Only the bad kind.
我们一定会抓住这家伙的
Hey, we're going to catch this guy.
是啊  抓住之后  还会有
Yeah, and when we do, there's going to be
下一个坏蛋等我们去抓
another one waiting for us,
一个又一个
and another, and another.
没有比这更让人沮丧的打地鼠游戏了
It's the most depressing game of Whack-a-Mole ever.
我们明白面对的是什么
Can't say we didn't know what we were getting into.
或者说再次面对什么
Or back into.
当我们决定留在斯特林市
When we decided to stay in Starling--
我是说  星城
I mean, hmm, Star City,
我很激动  我还以为这会是新的开始
I was excited. I thought it meant a new beginning.
但现在  我们只回来了一周
And now, we've only been back a week.
约翰还在生你的气  西娅变得不对劲
John is still mad at you, Thea's gone pit crazy,
我这两天一直在裁人
I've spent the last two days putting people out of work.
如果你认为我们这么做是错的  我们没有做错
If you think that we made a mistake, we didn't.
天上不会掉馅饼
Nothing worthwhile ever comes easy.
我们说过会换一种方式
We said that we were going to do things differently.
我们只是需要时间
We just need...time
来想出合适的方法
to figure out how.
兰斯队长
队长
Captain?
超重力俱乐部  第四大街与皮尔斯大街交界处
Heavy Heavy Club, 4th and Pierce
怎么了
What about it?
杰西卡·丹福斯的女儿
It's where Lonnie Machin
被朗尼·马尚扣押在那里
is holding Jessica Danforth's daughter.
你说过你会换一种方式
You said you're doing things differently now?
这就是你证明的机会
Here's your chance to prove it.
抱歉让你久等了
Sorry to leave you hanging.
我去见了个人  结果不太好
I had a meeting. It didn't go well.
看来  他们不愿意接纳我
Turns out, I can't sit at the cool kids' table.
当无数的粒子
When trillions and trillions
从小小针头炸裂的时候
of molecules exploded from a pin head,
有既定的法则指明如何开辟宇宙吗
were there rules dictating how to establish a universe?
没有
No.
万物在混乱中找到了出路
They found their way through the chaos.
求你了  你还是可以放我走
Please! You can still let me go!
除非你能保证
Only if you promise not to tell
不会把我的事情告诉别人
anybody about me.
拜托
Please!
拉钩钩吗
Pinky swear?
我改主意了
I changed my mind.
天啊
Oh, God!
我要对你做的事情...
Oh, the things I'm about to do to you...
就不能走前门吗
Something wrong with the front door?
放开那个女孩
Get away from the girl!
你能一小时后再来吗
Could you come back in an hour?
我们才刚刚开始
We were just getting started.
把绳子解开
Let's get her down.
费利西蒂
Felicity.
现在这个坏人已经知道你的搭档叫费利西蒂了
So now a mad man dujour knows you're working with a Felicity.
这就是我需要一个代号的原因
This is why I need a code name.
我们找到麦迪逊了  但是他溜走了
We have Madison, but he split.
在俱乐部外面没有人移动的痕迹
There's no movement outside the club.
他肯定还在里面
He must still be in there with you.
她需要治疗
She needs medical attention.
把她送到安全的地方  剩下的交给我们
Get her to safety. We've got this.
你能行吗
Can you handle this?
我可以
I'm good.
快手
Speedy!
快手  不要
Speedy, don't!
星城警局
宝贝
Baby?!
我的宝贝
Oh, my baby!
-过来  宝贝  -妈妈
- Come here, baby! - Mom!
我的宝贝
Oh, my baby, my baby.
太好了
Ok!
麦迪逊
Madison.
你还好吗
You all right?
只有点小擦伤
A few bumps and bruises,
这估计是世界上最糟糕的失眠症了
probably the world's worst case of insomnia.
真抱歉  但是外面有一堆记者在外面
I'm really sorry, but I got an army of reporters out there
他们想问下你是否愿意发表声明
and they want to know if you want to make a statement.
好的  我几分钟后出去
Yes, I'll be out in a few minutes.
你不必在今晚做这个
You don't have to do that tonight.
我需要  奥利弗
Yes, I do, Oliver.
我必须要告诉他们我已经决定好了
I have to tell them what I've decided.
我要退出竞选
I have to tell them I'm withdrawing my candidacy.
我不再参加市长竞选了
I'm not running for mayor.
来吧
Come on.
谢谢你信任我
Thank you for trusting me.
你说换一种方式真是不假
You weren't kidding about doing things differently, were you?
以前是用箭射他们
Instead of pin cushioning guys,
现在又把他们活活烧死吗
now you're burning them alive?
队长
Captain--
你很幸运
And you're lucky
马尚被送进了星城总医院
Machin is on his way to Starling General,
不然我会以谋杀罪名逮捕你
or I'd be booking you for murder.
你要清楚我们两人现在的立场
Just so you're clear where we stand with each other.
这个人需要水
This man needs some water!
听见我说话了吗
Did you hear me?
是的  我听见了
Yeah, I heard.
快回去工作
Get back to work.
如果你的工人都因为中暑死了
What are you going to do when all your workers
你们要怎么办
are dead from heat stroke?
和你没有关系
Not your concern.
听他说的
Like the man said,
回去工作
get back to work!
斯莫克小姐
Miss Smoak,
为什么我们听说
what's this we're hearing
你停止了裁员
about you halting the workforce reduction?
我以为我们达成了一致...
I thought we agreed--
当时是你说我听而已
Well, you talked and I listened.
我不认为那是达成一致
I would hardly call that an agreement.
我确实开除了一些人
With that said, I did get around to firing a few people
但是他们都又被重新雇佣了
they've all been hired back, B-T-dub.
他们其中的一个人让我想起了
And one of them reminded me
雷·帕尔默绝对不会同意这么做
that Ray Palmer never would have approved of this.
雷·帕尔默已经死了
Ray Palmer is dead.
而且这个公司也快破产了  除非...
And this company will be, too, unless--
我需要打断你一下
I am going to stop you right there.
抱歉  斯莫克小姐  你要见我吗
I'm sorry, Miss Smoak, you asked to see... me.
我想是弄错了
I think there's been a mistake.
没弄错  其实你来的正是时候
No, actually, you have perfect timing.
我正要和丹尼斯先生说到你的项目
I was just about to tell Mr. Dennis about your project.
在我解雇霍特先生后  我有机会
After I fired Mr. Holt, I had the opportunity
看了他正在进行的项目
to review his active projects.
原来他正在研究一些东西
It turns out he is working on something
而这将会给科技带来革命性的改变
that is going to revolutionize technology
并且拯救这家公司
and save this company.
没有足够的人员协助他
Neither of which he can do
他就无法完成这两项工作
with a reduced workforce supporting him.
有意思
Intriguing.
那这场科技大变革的内容是什么
So what's this revolutionary technology,
霍特先生
Mr. Holt?
那是专利
That is proprietary.
但我可以向你们担保  大变革会让世界震惊
But I can assure you, it will astonish the world.
我们半年后要召开年度股东大会
Our annual shareholders meeting's in six months.
到时给大家讲解吧
Present it there.
让我们震惊吧
Astonish us.
我们会的
Oh, we will.
你对所谓令世界震惊的科技
You don't even have an idea
根本就没有一点主意  对吧
for some world astonishing technology, do you?
没错  但我敢说你知道
Nope, but I am betting that you do.
帕尔默科技
相当大胆的举动啊  斯莫克小姐
Pretty bold move, Miss Smoak.
是的  我在尝试换一种方式做事
Yeah, well, I'm trying to do things a little differently.
有人吗
Hello?
你好吗
How are you?
我叫你别担心我
I guess I was wrong
看来是错的
when I told you not to worry about me.
对错与否  我还是会担心你
Right or wrong, I'm still going to worry.
这是当哥哥的首要职责
It's right at the top of the big brother job description.
西娅
Thea...
我当时应该立刻告诉你有关复活泉水的事
I should have told you about the Pit immediately.
那是过去的我
That was the old me.
那你现在变成什么样了
And who are you now?
奥利二代吗
Ollie 2.0?
不  我更像是
No, I'm more like...
尝试换一种方式做事的奥利一代
Ollie 1.0 who's trying to do things differently.
无论你在经历些什么
Look, whatever you are going through,
我们都会一起挺过去
we will get through it together.
我觉得西娅可以离开这里一段时间
I thought Thea could use some time out of town.
来个温泉度假  整理一下思绪
A spa getaway. Clear her head.
只要没有浴缸就行
As long as it's not near any hot tubs,
因为我落到这步田地都是因为那东西
'cause that's what got me into this situation.
我觉得这个主意不错
I think it's a good idea.
我们不在时  你和约翰能处理这的事情吗
Can you and John handle things while we're away?
好  前提我们没自相残杀
Yeah, as long as we don't kill each other first.
走了
Bye.
我刚是说笑的
I'm kidding, by the way.
我们不会有事的
We'll be fine.
也许吧
Probably.
好好照顾她  好吗
Take care of her, OK?
我和大家一样都很喜欢温泉
Yeah, I like a spa as much as anybody,
但我想我们都知道
but I think we both know
不管我在经历什么事
whatever is going on with me
美甲护理都于事无补
will not be fixed with a mani-pedi.
所以我们不会去泡温泉
That's why we're not going to the spa.
我们要去南达尔巴特
We're going to Nanda Parbat.
西娅  无论你在经历些什么
Thea, whatever's going on with you,
刺客联盟会知道该怎么做
the League, they'll know what to do.
为什么我们不告诉我哥哥
Why-why are we not telling my brother?
因为我们去南达尔巴特
Because you're not the only reason
不只是为了你
for us going to Nanda Parbat.
发生什么事了
What happened?
救护车没能到达星城总院
The ambulance didn't make it to Starling General.
我们试过用无线电联系救护人员
We tried to get the paramedics on the radio,
然后接到报警电话
and then we got a 911 call reporting this.
马尚  他...
Machin, he...
我真不知道该怎么描述他对他们做了什么
I don't really know how to describe what he did to them.
我不知道这符号是什么意思
I'm not sure what that symbol means.
这代表混乱
It means anarchy.
在吗
Hello.
我在这里
Hey, I'm out here.
你看起来很开心
You look happy.
别告诉我你开始享受解雇别人了
Don't tell me you started enjoying firing people.
不再解雇了
No more firing.
很好
Good.
想到别的办法了吗
Figured out another way.
也许你可以和我分享你的秘密
Well, maybe you could share your secret with me.
我承诺过自己  要换一种方式做事
Doing things differently is what I promised myself.
你现在就是在换一种方式做事啊
You are doing things differently.
显然方式改变得不够
Well, not different enough, apparently.
兰斯和杰西卡·丹福斯两人
Both Lance and Jessica Danforth
都对我说了同样的话
said something to me
他们说这座城市需要的东西
about this city needing something
绿箭侠无法给予
that the Green Arrow can't offer them.
一家好的寿司店吗
Decent Sushi restaurant?
是希望
Hope.
激励
Inspiration.
做事光明磊落之人
Someone who can do things in the light,
不会害怕
who isn't afraid...
能保护自我的人
someone who can protect himself.
费利西蒂
Felicity...
我要竞选市长
I'm going to run for mayor.
莎拉·兰斯
至爱的女儿 至爱的妹妹
1987-2007
你确定要这么做吗
Are you sure you want to do this?